Dario Del Giudice, PhD

ddelgiu@ncsu.edu orcid.org/0000-0002-6375-8527 2501 Stinson Dr., Raleigh, NC 27695

SUMMARY

A decade of experience in environmental engineering, analyzing and predicting human impacts on aquatic ecosystems. Expert in stochastic modeling for uncertainty quantification in environmental risk assessment. Successfully completed more than a dozen research projects aiming at improving water resources management while leading international teams across Europe and US.

EDUCATION

PhD, Environmental Engineering, Institutes of Technology (ETHZ, Eawag), Switzerland.	2011 - 2015
Thesis: Improving output and input statistical error descriptions in urban hydrological modeling.	
MSc, Environmental Sciences and Engineering, Institute of Technology (EPFL), Switz. Summa cum laude.	2009 - 2011
BSc Environmental Sciences Università di Bologna Italy Summa cum laude	2006 – 2009

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Postdoctoral Research Scholar, North Carolina State University, US. since 2018
Postdoctoral Researcher, Carnegie Institution at Stanford University, US. 2015 – 2018

PEER-REVIEWED PUBLICATIONS

- 1. **D. Del Giudice**, V. Matli, D. Obenour. Bayesian mechanistic modeling characterizes Gulf of Mexico hypoxia: 1968-2016 and future scenarios. *Ecol. Appl.* (2019), https://doi.org/10.1002/eap.2032.
- 2. A. Katin, **D. Del Giudice**, D. Obenour. Modeling biophysical controls on hypoxia in a shallow estuary using a Bayesian mechanistic approach. *Environ. Modell. Soft.* (2019), https://doi.org/10.1016/j.envsoft.2019.07.016.
- 3. S. Fang, **D. Del Giudice**, et al. A space-time geostatistical model for probabilistic estimation of harmful algal bloom biomass and areal extent. *Sci. Total Environ.* (2019), https://doi.org/10.1016/j.scitotenv.2019.133776.
- 4. D. Machac, P. Reichert, J. Rieckermann, **D. Del Giudice**, C. Albert. Accelerating Bayesian inference in hydrological modelling with a mechanistic emulator. *Environ. Modell. Soft.* (2018), doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2018.07.016.
- 5. **D. Del Giudice**, M. Kalcic, R. Muenic, N. Bosch, D. Scavia et al. On the practical usefulness of least squares for assessing uncertainty in hydrologic and water quality predictions. *Environ. Modell. Soft.* (2018), doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2018.03.009.
- 6. **D. Del Giudice**, Y. Zhou, E. Sinha, A. Michalak. Long-term phosphorus loading and springtime temperatures explain interannual variability of hypoxia in a large temperate lake. *Environ. Sci. Technol.* (2018), doi: 10.1021/acs.est.7b04730.
- 7. **D. Del Giudice**, C. Albert, J. Rieckermann, P. Reichert. Describing the catchment-averaged precipitation as a stochastic process improves parameter and input estimation. *Water Res. Res.* (2016), doi: 10.1002/2015WR017871.
- 8. A. Sikorska, **D. Del Giudice**, K. Banasik, J. Rieckermann. The value of streamflow data in improving TSS predictions Bayesian multi-objective calibration. *J. Hydrol.* (2015), doi:10.1016/j.jhydrol.2015.09.051.
- 9. **D. Del Giudice**, R. Löwe, H. Madsen, P. Mikkelsen, J. Rieckermann. Comparison of two stochastic techniques for reliable urban runoff predictions by modeling systematic errors. *Water Res. Res.* (2015), doi: 10.1002/2014WR016678.
- 10. **D. Del Giudice**, V. Bares, C. Albert, P. Reichert, J. Rieckermann. Model bias and complexity understanding the effects of structural deficits and input errors on runoff predictions. *Environ. Modell. Soft.* (2015), doi:10.1016/j.envsoft.2014.11.006.
- 11. D. Dürrenmatt, **D. Del Giudice**, J. Rieckermann. Dynamic time warping improves sewer flow monitoring. *Water Res.* (2013), doi: 10.1016/j.watres.2013.03.051.
- 12. **D. Del Giudice**, M. Honti, A. Scheidegger, C. Albert, P. Reichert, J. Rieckermann. Improving uncertainty estimation in urban hydrological modeling by statistically describing bias. *Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sci.*, (2013), doi:10.5194/hess-17-4209-2013.
- 13. S. Coutu, **D. Del Giudice**, L. Rossi, D. Barry. Parsimonious hydrological modeling of urban sewer and river catchments. *J. Hydrol.* (2012), doi:10.1016/j.jhydrol.2012.07.039.

Dario Del Giudice CURRICULUM VITAE

14. S. Coutu, **D. Del Giudice**, L. Rossi, D. Barry. Modeling of facade leaching in urban catchments. *Water Res. Res.* (2012), doi:10.1029/2012WR012359.

OTHER PUBLICATIONS

D. Del Giudice, A. Davies. A few words can make a big impact. Nature (2017), doi: 10.1038/541030e.

D. Del Giudice. Evidence-based critical thinking. Science (2016), doi: 10.1126/science.354.6308.46.

TEACHING & MENTORING

Invited Lecturer for Hydrology and Urban Water Systems (NCSU), >60 students.	2018
Invited Speaker for the Academic Chats Program (Stanford U.) - help students aspiring to faculty	careers. 2017
Facilitator for Science Communication Workshops (Stanford U.) - mentor grad students	2016 - 2017
and postdocs to effectively present their research; ~30 students.	
Advisor for: R. Fu, C. Rachelly (ETHZ), P. Kornberger (U. Rapperswil), D. Eilertz (U. Freiburg) T. Doppler (Eawag), E. Grava (U. Neuchatel), T. Rossboth (U. Vienna), S. Fang, A. Katin, Y. Ha	
TA for Environmental Systems Analysis (Eawag) – summer school on Bayesian inference, model predictions, and uncertainty quantification with R; ~30 students.	2012 – 2015
TA for graduate and undergraduate courses (ETHZ):	2012 2014

TA for graduate and undergraduate courses (ETHZ):

- 2012 2014
- Urban water management (essentials) water supply, rainfall analysis, and dimensioning the sewer system. I assisted in the design and grading of the exams; ~100 students.
- Urban water management (advanced) urban hydrology and hydraulics and pollutant transport computation. I assisted in the design and grading of the exams; ~20 students.

TA for graduate and undergraduate courses (EPFL):

2010 - 2011

2018

- Water Quality Modeling hydrogeochemical computation, contaminant degradation, and reaction kinetics. I led the exercise sessions and graded the assignments and exams; ~20 students.
- Quantitative Methods II analysis of mathematical models for environmental engineering.
 I led the exercises with Matlab and graded the assignments and exams; ~40 students.
- Air Pollution Modeling emission and dispersion forecasting.
 I led the exercise sessions and graded the assignments; ~30 students.
- Informatics provided IT support for students on software and computational issues.

HONORS & AWARDS (SELECTED)

Individual of Extraordinary Ability LISCIS LIS

Individual of Extraordinary Ability, USCIS, US.	2018
Best Paper Award, Urban Drainage Modeling Conference, Serbia. 1 prize awarded over > 170 papers	2012
Veolia Award for the most innovative project in water sciences, France. 1 prize awarded over > 50 candidates.	2011
Société de géomatique Prize for the best grade , Switzerland. 1 prize awarded over ~ 50 students.	2011
"Mention of excellence," École polytechnique fédérale de Lausanne, Switzerland.	2011
Environment Prize for an excellent thesis , Switzerland. 1 prize awarded over ~ 50 students.	2011
Grivat Scholarship for the $most\ meritorious$ student, Switzerland. 1 grant awarded over ~ 150 students	2010
Award for outstanding performance during an internship, Switzerland.	2010
$\textbf{Excellence Scholarship} \ \ \text{for outstanding performance, Switzerland.} \ \sim \! 10 \ \text{grants awarded over} \sim \! 1000 \ \text{students}$	2009
European Union Scholarship to study at Universidad de Granada, Spain. 1 grant awarded over ~ 100 students	2008

Dario Del Giudice CURRICULUM VITAE

CONFERENCE PRESENTATIONS (SELECTED)

D. Del Giudice , S. Fang, D. Scavia, D. Obenour. Bayesian mechanistic modeling elucidates controls on bloom timing and magnitude in Western Lake Erie. <i>Conference on Great Lakes Research</i> , Brockport, US.	2019
A. Katin, D. Del Giudice , H. Paerl, D. Obenour. Modeling biophysical controls on hypoxia for the Neuse River Estuary using a Bayesian framework. <i>Coastal Modeling Conference</i> , Seattle, US.	2018
Michalak, A.M., V. Balaji, D. Del Giudice , et al. Are extreme hydrometeorological events a prerequisite for extreme water quality impacts? <i>AGU Meeting (Invited)</i> , New Orleans, US.	2017
D. Del Giudice et al. Balancing the stochastic description of uncertainties as a function of hydrologic model complexity. <i>AGU Meeting (Invited)</i> , San Francisco, US.	2016
D. Del Giudice et al. Beyond rainfall multipliers: describing input uncertainty as an autocorrelated stochastic process improves inference in hydrology. <i>AGU Meeting</i> , San Francisco, US.	2015
K. Villez, D. Del Giudice , M. Neumann, and J. Rieckermann. The statistical description of model bias. <i>Watermatex Symposium on Systems Analysis</i> , Gold Coast, Australia.	2015
R. Löwe, D. Del Giudice , H. Madsen, P. Mikkelsen, and J. Rieckermann. Probabilistic modelling in urban drainage. <i>Conference on Urban Drainage</i> , Kuching, Malaysia.	2014
D. Del Giudice , V. Bares, C. Albert, P. Reichert, and J. Rieckermann. Selecting optimal hydrodynamic model complexity. <i>AGU Meeting</i> , San Francisco, US.	2013
D. Del Giudice , P. Reichert, M. Honti, A. Scheidegger, C. Albert, and J. Rieckermann. Improving prediction uncertainty estimation in urban hydrology. <i>EGU Conference</i> , Vienna, Austria.	2013
D. Del Giudice, S. Coutu, L. Rossi, and A. Barry.Modelling the behavior of facade biocides. <i>Urban Drainage Conference</i>, Belgrade, Serbia.	2012
INVITED TALKS	
Statistic and mechanistic modeling to understand and predict oxygen depletion. U. Maryland, US.	2018
Impacts of climate variability on hydrology and water quality. Temple U., Rice U. and U. Florida, US.	2018
Predicting the impacts of climate change on hydrological systems. Sandia National Labs, US.	2017
Improving estimation and predictions in hydrology and water quality. UC Irvine, US.	2017
Combining modeling and statistics to predict hydrologic and water quality dynamics. Stanford U., US.	2017
How to get reliable predictions despite model bias? Met Office, UK.	2014
Impacts of input and structural errors. U. Lausanne and Institute for Forest Research, Switzerland.	2014
Give me a model and I will tell you what its uncertainty is. <i>U. Tübingen</i> and <i>U. Stuttgart</i> , Germany.	2014
Bayesian uncertainty analysis accounting for bias. DTU, Denmark and U. Innsbruck, Austria.	2013
Modeling biocides leaching at basin scale Forschungszentrum liilich Germany and TU Wien Austria	2011

JOURNAL REVIEWER

Water Resour. Res., Stoch. Env. Res. Risk A., Environ. Modell. Softw., Water Sci. Technol., J. Hydrol., Hydrol. Earth Syst. Sc., Computat. Geosci., Environ. Sci. Technol., Geophys. Res. Lett., Environ. Pollut.

LANGUAGE SKILLS

Italian (native), English (fluent), French (fluent), Spanish (fluent), German (fluent), Latin (interm.), Portuguese (interm.).